IT MANAGER

Professional Profile

I have been working in the IT industry for more than 15 years, mostly as a Team Lead or IT Project Manager. My best qualities are my excellent communication and organizational skills. I have managed budgets, inventory, security, fault tolerance, staff, backups, availability, migrations, deployments, and the overall health of company infrastructure. My goal is to find a challenging and fun environment where I can leverage my skills and lead my fellow team members into higher productivity and efficiency.

Qualifications

- Data Center Migration
- IT Team Lead
- IT Manager
- System Administrator
- DevOps Engineer
- Scripting and Automation
- Provisioning and Patching
- Security and Backups
- Performance and Tuning
- Continuous Integration

Relevant Experience

In addition to being an IT Project Manager, I have been the lead on several high profile projects such as desktop integration for the Java Development Environment at Sun Microsystems. I was the project lead for moving an entire data center at Cisco. I led a project at Sun Microsystems to synchronize Enterprise contacts, email, and calendar to employee smart phones. I converted an entire heterogeneous data center from NIS to LDAP by myself.

Experience

10/2015 to Current

IT Manager City Of Austin, Tx i1/4 Austin, TX

- Managed an elite team of talented IT professionals.
- Utilized Citrix XenApp, XenDesktop, and Imprivata OneSign to enable medical staff to access medical records from anywhere at Kaiser Permanente with a single tap of their facility badge.
- Supported over a million users to "Single Sign On" and get through several layers of security to access "KPHC" (Kaiser Permanente Health Connect).
- Supported Oracle Enterprise Manager as part of the Identity Management piece of the Single Sign On solution at Kaiser Permanente.
- Did patch upgrades across the enterprise on Oracle enterprise and Imprivata.
- Supported WaveID card readers and agents using PCProxyConfig to troubleshoot issues.
- Supported shared workstations for medical staff to access medical records utilizing Epic and Citrix Xenapp.
- Maintained multiple datacenters with proprietary Imprivata Linux Appliances.

02/2015 to 07/2015

IT Manager / System Administrator City Of Austin, Tx i1/4 Austin, TX

- Managed team consisting of a DBA, several Linux/Unix Engineers, and several desktop support people.
- Responsible for physical and virtual Suse and Redhat based DevOps systems.
- Created BASH scripts using Expect and NMAP to generate reports and automatically populate Nagios configuration files.
- Responsible for end user laptops and troubleshooting end user issues for Windows 7 and 8.1.
- Worked with HP Service Manager to resolve tickets and work on IT projects.
- Worked with HP Service Automation, Insight Manager, and VMware Virtual Center to provision new test systems.
- Worked with a customized and automated provisioning system for new laptops.
- Worked extensively with Kickstart to provision new virtual and physical machines.
- Worked with HP C7K and Proliant servers, Hitachi, NetApp, and EMC storage.

06/2013 to 02/2015

IT Manager / System Administrator Svb Financial Group il/4 Sonoma, CA

- Managed team consisting of several multi talented engineers, a superior DBA, a VMware expert, and several front line support staff.
- Managed all GIT servers and storage devices.
- Was responsible for adding access and group membership to GIT REPOS.
- Managed, Agile, Jenkins, Bugzilla, and other company specific applications.
- Responsible for granting account access to NIS, Active Directory, Application Servers, and solving end user issues like VPN and resetting of passwords.
- Responsible for maintaining 3par corporate NIS, LDAP, and Active Directory.
- Wrote scripts for tracking space usage by user and by workspace.
- Wrote scripts for account creation and removal.
- Utilized P2V, V2V, and P2P using VMware converter.
- Set policy objects in Active Directory for account access and privileges on the network.
- Managed multi-tiered web architecture over J2EE, web services, and shared storage using Fiber Channel.

10/2011 to 06/2013

IT Manager 22Nd Century Technologies il/4 Bothell, WA

• Department manager of several DevOps teams and data center environments.

- Migrated Win2k8 and Win2k12 domain controllers from Virtual to Physical.
- Managed three Virtual (VMware) and Physical (Cisco UCS, HP C7K, Proliant) networks in Houston, Austin, and San Jose.
- Responsible for all interfaces, wiring, switches, routers, power, and cooling.
- Managed a virtualization initiative to consolidate lab resources into a smaller space, energy, and administrative footprint.
- Supported development teams to restructure server, network, and storage environments.
- Implemented several custom vCloud implementations for the San Jose, Houston, and Austin labs.
- Integrated Active Directory accounts into Virtual Center to manage permissions and resource objects and connect to SQL Server 2K8.

03/2009 to 10/2011

IT Team Lead Svb Financial Group i1/4 Columbus, OH

- Created custom Nagios solution for Lab environment and core infrastructure.
- Created custom BASH scripts to automate the process of populating Nagios with systems and services.
- Worked with networking and systems engineers to tailor a solution of monitoring that best suits the needs of the department.
- Monitored core infrastructure switches, routers, and storage devices via SNMP, with Nagios and MRTG for things like fans, ports, throughput, FRU modules, etc..
- Created scripts to automate the process of adding new devices to Nagios and MRTG.
- Created Redhat Satellite Server for creating new virtual and physical machines with Kickstart and Cobbler.
- Did troubleshooting of devices that were alarming in Nagios for things like high load averages, stale file handles, full root partitions, system up or down, NRPE agent not running, network throughput slow, system swapping and caching, iowaits causing high load averages, etc..
- Monitored APS PDUs via SNMP for things like core fans, LED, sockets used, volts, and amps etc..
- Wrote extensive expect scripts to enable hosts to be Nagios clients and to copy over the trusted keys, systat, and other programs, plugins, and configuration file changes.

01/2009

System Administrator 22Nd Century Technologies il/4 Burkeville, VA

- Built HPC Clusters for mapping genomes.
- Worked side by side with scientists and PhD's.
- Primary Life Technologies point of contact between Universities, Hospitals, and Science Labs.
- Customers were Johns Hopkins, Monsanto, UCLA, USC, and many Universities and Science Labs around the globe.
- Assisted customers with the installation of Bioscope on their infrastructure and on Life Technologies "Solid Instrument".
- Installed Torque, SGE, Maui, SKYLD, Rocks, Bioscope, SLURM.
- Supported customers all over the globe troubleshooting Bioscope.
- Setup Nagios monitoring server for HPC Clusters.
- Setup CentOS RPM Repository with failover.
- Setup Redhat Enterprise Cluster.
- Worked with Penguin Computing and Dell servers and storage solutions.
- Installed ESXi 4.0 for testing software on virtual servers.
- Supported Solid Instruments [Genome mapping and pairing Hardware/Software].
- Assisted developers by making hardware/firmware changes to support better performance for the newest software updates and releases.
- Created scripts to facilitate the managing of jobs in the SGE/Torque queues.
- Wrote Nagios plugins in Perl and BASH for monitoring HPC cluster queues like torque and SGE.

06/2007 to 01/2009

IT Team Lead 22Nd Century Technologies i1/4 Columbia, MO

- Coordinated effort to RFID tag all parts in the worldwide corporate refinery inventory.
- Coordinated effort to implement Maximo, WebLogic, and Actuate iServer installation and patch upgrades.
- Coordinated effort to develop On Demand content integration for Maximo.
- Project lead to track payroll and HR with IBM Maximo.
- Peer review of enhancement packages Java classes, JSP, SQL, and documentation.
- Performed solution design and configuration of LDAP integration.
- Troubleshooting of MEA interface and JMS messaging.
- DB configuration, and Oracle triggers.
- Managed Corporate Active Directory user and group management.
- Responsible for creating aliases and groups for Exchange server to send out alerts to various technical teams and user groups.

01/2006

System Administrator First Tech Credit Union i1/4 Fort Collins, CO

- Upgraded NIS to LDAP in a 50 plus system environment of mixed Solaris, Linux, and Windows clients.
- Set up auto mounting for both Solaris and Linux clients with LDAP Sun Directory Server 5.2.
- Upgraded firmware on NetApp NAS servers to enable LDAP protocol.
- Setup OpenSSL and TLS to run on port 636 of the directory server so that LDAP client requests are challenged and communications are encrypted on the network.
- Used the OpenSSL certutil tools to setup a local CA and sign my own certificates.

- Setup iPlanet Web server.
- Upgraded VERITAS NetBackup from version 4.5 to version 5.1 MP3.
- Improved the performance of the NetBackup configuration by setting the memory properties in the /etc/sysconfig file on the master server.
- Changed the backup policies to include multi-streaming for speed.
- Upgraded firmware, controllers, and drives on the tape storage library.
- Backed up Exchange Server mail boxes.
- Worked with tape storage library.

09/2005 to 06/2007

System Administrator Adt Security Services, Inc i1/4 Saint Rose, LA

- Led a project to migrate all systems from the Wiley network to the Computer Associates network.
- I worked together with corporate security teams to ensure that all systems were properly scanned and hardened before adding them to the corporate network.
- Conducted a project to clone and replicate systems that took a week to build for QA testing.
- Led a project to move an entire data center from Brisbane to Redwood Shores.
- I was responsible for tracking inventory, host names, IP addresses, labeling, network drops, power, and the functionality of the network and systems after the move.
- Led a project to create software to identify computer system owners, whether or not they're still being used, If they're IP addresses can be reclaimed, the re-imaging or building of the reclaimed machine, the issuance of the IP address to the new system owners, and the installation of OS, and applications.

01/2005

Web Engineer Sentinel Technologies Inc i1/4 Uniontown, OH

- Performed trouble shooting for Wells Fargo & Company Online Banking environment using HP OpenView, Mercury Topaz, and custom monitoring tools.
- Monitored and interpreted log files to determine source of problems.
- Routed online traffic using customized load balancing and DNS tools such as BigIP F5.
- Took application instances, platforms, or data centers out of rotation for emergencies and scheduled maintenance.
- Opened and directed technical bridge lines for problems requiring multiple production support groups to resolve.
- Performed checkouts for production applications before placing them into rotation.
- Used start and stop scripts for Bea WebLogic 8.1, SunOne Web Server 6.1, and other applications.
- Updated Frontline Procedures, Escalation Procedures, Business Resumption Plans, and project specific documents for departmental and business wide use.
- Created change requests, trouble tickets, and other tracking functionality using Remedy.

01/2004

NOC Analyst Walmart.com i1/4 City, STATE

- Troubleshooting and escalating production environment failures relating to the website on a 24x7 basis.
- Single point of contact for all website, production malfunctions.
- Ability to multitask under pressure to complete tasks while exceeding expectations.
- Orchestrated conference calls with many individuals and teams representing a range of technical disciplines in order to resolve critical issues.
- Ran scripts to change out tapes in libraries, push search tables in databases, update the scratch pools on the NetBackup media servers, poll the tape libraries for currently available tapes, and run backup reports.
- Used Proactive Net to monitor all daemons, services, and network interfaces.
- Managed networks of remote servers, agents, and systems.
- Monitored Solaris production environment, which included servers, databases, reports, tape backups, and x86 Solaris.
- Handled and worked on code releases, code deployments, and code patches to production servers.
- Initiated corrective action through provided tools to assist third-party business partners, customers and vendors with problem isolation and resolution.
- Used MRTG to monitor inbound and outbound network traffic.
- Worked with tape storage library.

01/2000 to 05/2005

IT Project Manager Sun Microsystems il/4 City, STATE

- Project Lead building four usability labs, interviewed vendors, took competing bids, tracked progress, managed vendor installation, and came in under budget and weeks ahead of time.
- Project Lead for conducting usability studies.
- Project lead on creation of the Java Desktop Environment.
- Project lead synchronizing enterprise data with employee smart phones.
- Implemented network changes to the corporate infrastructure and worked together with multiple teams and vendors.
- Made drawings and hosted meetings.
- Did all the recording, mixing, and editing of the usability study videos and distributed the results by streaming them with Real Media Server.
- Belonged to the Bay Area Streaming Media Users Group and hosted meetings to better learn how leaders in other companies were using

streaming media.

- Other BASMUG members represented AMD, Intel, Oracle, and many other prominent bay area companies.
- Conducted reverse auctions with bidders worldwide to do the localization for Star Office.
- Conducted a video conferenced usability study with the Hamburg Star Office L10N team, the Yokohama L10N team, and the Menlo Park Usability team all participating and viewing the studies simultaneously.
- I did all the coordination of reserving the conference room, preparing the equipment and environment, and ensuring that the video conferencing went off smoothly.

Education

2000

Solaris Administration I and II Sun University i1/4 City, State, US

- Solaris System Administration
- Signal Processing
- Scripting and Provisioning
- Storage and Backups
- Clusters and HA

2000

Storage Management with Backup Sun University i1/4 City, State, US

- Tape Storage Libraries
- Legato Networker
- Symantec NetBackup
- Storage Concepts

1992

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science Cal State Fullerton il/4 City, State, US

- Data Structures
- Data Objects
- Top Down Programming
- Procedures and Functions
- Arrays
- C++

Affiliations

• BASMUG - Bay Area Streaming Media Users Group

Skills

Active Directory, Actuate, administrative, Agile, APS, automate, Automation, Backup, tape backups, Banking, BASH, Budgeting, budgets, budget, Cisco, Citrix, CA, Hardware, network and systems, consulting, content, Costing, client, clients, Client Relations, DBA, databases, database development, Dell servers, documentation, DNS, editing, Electronics, Functional, HP, HP OpenView, HR, IBM, imaging, Intel, inventory, IP, iPlanet, J2EE, Java, JMS, JSP, laptops, LDAP, Team Building, Leadership, Linux, managing, Max, meetings, memory, Mentoring, messaging, access, Exchange Server, mail, Windows 7, Windows, Win2, MP3, Enterprise, NAS, network, networking, networks, NIS, OS, Oracle Enterprise Manager, Oracle, DB, payroll, Peer review, Perl, PhD, policies, Presentations, progress, Project Lead, Project Management, Proliant, quality, QA, Real Estate, recording, Redhat, Requirements Analysis, routers, San, Scheduling, Servers, scripts, SNMP, sockets, Software Development, testing software, Solaris, SQL, SQL Server 2, Star Office, Streaming Media, Sun, Supervision, switches, systems engineering, tables, desktop support, phones, troubleshoot, trouble shooting, Troubleshooting, UNIX System, Unix, upgrades, Vendor Management, NetBackup, VERITAS NetBackup, video, video conferencing, VPN, web architecture, Web Server 6.1, Web server, website, WebLogic, wiring, x86